给我张支票,  什么意思?
What is the meaning of this check?
要我踢假球?
Do you want me to cheat?
不是…  我是中间人
No...
我只不过是受人所托
I'm just the middleman.
你是耍我,  还是要害我?
Do you play fast and loose with me, or cause me trouble?
你别以为我倒下,  你就可爬上去
Don't you think you'll be ahead of me...
你想都别想
...if I fall?
你给我看清楚
Look at this!
黄金右脚,  是我,  不是你
I'm the only Golden Leg!
想超越我,  想都别想
You can't daydream about that.
我真的不敢想,  我最近手头紧
No... I don't.
我想抽点佣金,  你千万不要告诉别人
I just want to have some tick-back. Please don't tell anybody.
你这个败类,  连狗都不如
You're trash!
对不起!  锋哥,  我先走了
I'm sorry. Catch you later.
黄金右脚…
Golden Leg...
强雄哥,  你称霸球坛二十年
Hung, you've been a star player for twenty years.
自从黄金右脚射失十二码受伤之后
Since Fung missed the penalty kick and lost his golden leg,
你就一直未逢敌手,  那么现在你…
you ever have any rivals. Now your feeling is...
不开心的事就不要再提了
Oh, no! Don't talk about this!
强雄哥,  你的魔鬼队
Hung, your Evil Team...
连续五届超级杯从没打输
...has already won the gold for five years.
究竟有什么秘密?
What's the secret?
秘密?  谁是领队就是秘密
Secret? The secret is having the great soccer coach.
那今年的超级杯应该是志在必得了?
So you should have confidence to get the gold again.
你第一天做记者?  这个问题还用问
Are you first time to be a reporter? I don't think you should ask this question.
各位,  对不起…
Excuse me...
雄哥,  早
Good morning, Hung!
黄金右脚
Golden Leg!
雄哥,  早
Good morning, Hung!
早
Good morning!
雄哥,  你的鞋脏了
Hung, your shoe is dirty.
我帮你擦干净
I help you to clean it up.
不用…  我自己来
It's fine. I can manage.
雄哥,  我去开车
Hung, I'll take your car over.
雄哥,  你不是说让我带球队吗?
Hung, you promise to offer a coaching job to me.
我可以了,  我准备好了
I'm ready.
我一定把他们训练得像魔鬼队般厉害
I've confidence to train a team as good as the Evil Team.
你这德性还可以带队吗?
Do you think you still can be a coach?
收山吧!
Forget it.
不是,  雄哥,  你不是说…
But you said...
我说说嘛!  人是要面对现实的
Get real.
你看你,  那条腿瘸成那样
You see. You're a cripple now.
你以为你还可以靠这四个字混饭吃吗?
Don't you think you still can depend on this tattoo?
雄哥
Hung...
我跟你这么多年
I've served you for twenty years.
你现在跟我说这种话?
How can you say such thing?
我今天心情不好,  人是会变的
Today, I'm not in the mood. Things change.
你那时候挺帅的
You looked great when you were young.
你看看你,  现在变成这德性
You see, you just look like a dog right.
回乡去吧!
Forget it. Got lost.
我养了你二十年了
I've already taken care of you for twenty years.
人至义尽,  盒饭钱不少的
You know, it is a great deal of money.
强雄
Hung!
你不要这么过份
You're so vain!
要不是二十年前你给我一张空头支票
If you didn't give me...
叫我踢假球,  断送了这条腿
...the dishonour check twenty years ago,
我今天会变成这样?
I wouldn't be crippled now.
干什么?  发脾气?  大声点
What? Are you loosing your temper? Why don't you shout loudly!
喂!  你们听见没有?
Hey! Did all you guys hear that?
外面有记者,  要不要把他们叫进来?
There're thousands of reporters outside. Would you like me to let them come in?
你以为我养你二十年为什么?
You know,
就是堵住你这张臭嘴
I keep you here to shut your mouth.
你看你臭要饭的样子
Do you think anyone would trust...
人家会不会信你呢?
...a handicapped beggar as you now?
- 你…     - 别生气…
- You!     - Don't be angry.
如果要怪,  就怪你自己
If you want to blame anyone, that one should be you.
贪心
You should blame your greediness.
回乡去吧!
Forget it.
再告诉你一件事
Tell you one more thing.
当年打断你腿的那帮人,  也是我安排
I was the one who arranged the accident to your leg.
有什么了不起的
Damn it!
球…不是这么踢的
It's no way to kick like that.
你说什么?
Pardon?
我说球…
I said...
并不是这么踢的
...it was no way to kick like that.
那…应该怎么踢呀?
So what's your opinion?
一句话: 腰马合一
There has to be a fusion of the strength from the waist and foot.
何谓腰马合一?
What's that?
腰马合一,  是我心目中浩气长存的
My idol, Bruce Lee,
已故伟大武术家—李小龙先生已解释过
had already elaborated about it.
但是如果你想再多了解一点
If you want to learn more,
那就跟我学两堂功夫
you can take two kung fu lessons from me.
学什么功夫?
Learning kung fu?
看你的样子,  还不是在这儿扫地
You just look like a cleaner.
扫地只是我的表面工作
Cleaner is just my job.
我真正的身份是一位研究僧
My real identity is a post-graduate student.
研究僧?
Post-graduate student?
从事如何有效率地
Focusing on how to...
发扬少林武功的研究工作
...effectively develop Shaolin kung fu.
这张是我的名片
This's my name card.
少林正宗大力金刚腿
Shaolin Orthodox School Mighty Steel Leg.
是,  很大力的
Look! It's really strong.
打打杀杀,  你找别人吧!
Fighting is not my style.
我受过高等教育的
I'm an well-educated man.
错了
You're wrong.
你看那个靓女
Look at that girl.
靓女又怎么样?
I know she's sexy, so what?
- 我是读书人     - 不…
- But I'm an educated...     - No...
你看…
Look at this!
如果她会少林的轻功
If she had learned Shaolin kung fu, Weight Vest,
就不会发生这种事了
she would not have fallen like this.
你看
You see!
所以说,  武功的确是棒
So Shaolin kung fu is great!
小姐,  有没有兴趣学功夫?
Hey! Do you want to learn kung fu?
神经病
You're crazy!
你再看看那边那位太太
Look at the woman over there.
如果她会少林的铁沙掌
If she had studied Shaolin kung fu, Iron Hand,
泊车就不用这么愁了
parking would be much easier.
所以说,  武功的确是行
So kung fu is wonderful!
太太,  有没有兴趣学…
Excuse me! Do you want to learn...
行了…  那边要去
Okay... Get lost me!
这一毛钱我也有份
This coin is not just yours. I should have a share.
别这么扫兴
Don't do that to ruin our relationship!
你再看看那边
Look at that!
你剪什么?
What's wrong?
剪棵树剪了一年?
You've already spent a whole year to trim the tree.
你不用开工了,  走
You're fired. Get away!
- 对不起…     - 走吧!
- I'm sorry...     - Get away!
如果那个工人会少林的独孤九剑
If he had studied Shaolin kung fu, Nine Fence of the Recluse,
哪用那么麻烦?
he would not be in trouble!
独孤九剑,  好像是华山派
Nine Fence of the Recluse seems came from Hua Shan.
天下武功出少林,  你没听过吗?
Don't you know all kinds of kung fu originated from Shaolin?
功夫其实绝对是适合男女老幼的
Kung fu is absolutely good for different ages.
打打杀杀只是大家对它的误解
Brutality is just the wrong impression of kung fu.
功夫更加是一种艺术
Kung fu is an art,
一种不屈的精神
one kind of indomitable spirit.
所以一直以来我都在找方法
I'm looking for a good method...
想将功夫重新包装起来
...to package Shaolin kung fu...
使得你们这些升斗小民
...and then let people understand...
对功夫能够有更深一层的了解
...the true meaning of it.
好啦…
Enough, already!
我还没说完呢!
I've not finished yet.
差不多了…
Almost finished.
我还有几个客人要见呢!
I still have some appointments with my clients.
今天就这样吧!
It's done.
你把握机会好不好?
Please seize your opportunity!
瘸子也可以练功夫的
The lame can also learn kung fu.
瘸什么瘸?  瘸你妈的
What are you talking about? Who's the lame?
你这傻瓜有什么资格说我瘸?
You're not qualified to talk soccer with me.
对不起
I'm sorry!
是呀!  我是瘸
Yes, I'm the lame.
怎么样?  你有的瘸吗?
It's none of your business.
瘸?
The lame?
瘸你妈的
Bullshit!
怎么?
What?
唬我呀?
Do you think that would scare me?
这垃圾你收不收?  不收我给别人了
Do you still want the garbage? If you don't, I'll call the other one.
收…
I'm coming over.
动作快点
Hurry up!
怎么?  唬我呀?
Do you think that would scare me?
走…  走呀!
Get out of here...
麻烦你,  帮我把冰箱搬上去
Excuse me! Would you help me to pick it over there?
好,  来
No problem!
腿这么厉害
Your leg is so great!
- 两毛钱     - 两毛钱?
- Twenty cents!     - Oh, no! Just twenty cents?
里面又杯子、又碟子,  多给一毛钱吧!
There are some cups and plates inside. Would you give me ten more cents?
没了…没有多啦…
No more!
阿华,  把它搬过去
Wah, move it over there.
阿梅,  给我来十个馒头
Mui, please give me ten steamed bread!
太极功夫做馒头 惊天动地
Using Tai Chi kung fu to make steamed bread is a startling idea.
馒头看来又香又甜 谁都想吃
The steamed bread looks sweet and tasty.
但见阿妹双臂好力
I'm so impressed...
令到阿哥五体投地
...by her strong arms.
你…
You...
你干什么?
What are you doing?
除了唱歌,  我想不到其他方法
Singing is the exceptional way...
来表达我内心的兴奋和对你的仰慕
for me to express my true feeling of esteem.
好正点
So beautiful!
我不好看,  你别笑我
I'm not beautiful. Don't laugh at me!
你看这馒头多正点啊!
You see! The steamed bread is so great!
好吃
Taste wonderful!
你刚才那招太极拳的移形换影…
Your Tai Chi kung fu, Shifting Bodies and Transposing Shadows...
是以柔克刚,  四两拨千斤
It's a firm but gentle kung fu, Shove a Thousand Cattle with Four Tales.
好
Well!
怪不得这馒头刚中有柔,  硬中又有软
That's why the steamed bread is so tender and tough.
馒头五毛钱一个,  两个一块
Fifty cents per each. Two-steamed bread is one dollar.
- 这么贵?     - 是呀!
- So expensive!     - Really.
所以说,  真是一分钱一分货
Even though it's so expensive, it's worth.
我刚好身上有五毛钱
I just have fifty cents right now.
剩下过两天再给行不行?
Would you mind I'll pay you back two days later?
不行
Nope.
好!  学武之人讲句话都这么洒脱
Well! You're a typical kung fu master speaking with grace and ease.
其实我也是个武林中人
You know, we get something in common. I'm also a Shaolin master.
给点面子好不好?
Would you give me a face-saving permission?
不好
No.
好
Okay!
我这双名贵球鞋原价两块钱
Here are some fine sneakers.
因为你,  算一块五
I'll give them to you,
我就多拿你一个馒头就好啦!
if you let me have one more bun.
- 我报警了     - 好
- I'll call the cops.     - Fine.
法律不外乎人情
Come on, give me a break.
糟了,  靓女,  我越看你越漂亮
You're so beautiful.
你别唱了
Shut up!
你别再唱了
Please stop singing.
你把钱给我,  赶快走吧!
Just pay and get out of here.
你要唱歌的话,  到那边山上去唱
If you want to sing, do it on the mountain.
神经病才在这里唱歌呢!
Only crazy people sing here.
我不同意这位小姐的说法
I disagree with the young lady.
在这里唱歌,  不一定都是神经病
Just because you sing out loud here doesn't make you a lunatic.
我叫酱爆
My name is Dynamite.
我从来没有放弃
My dream is...
成为一个伟大作曲家的理想
...to become a great composer one day.
刚才听到这位先生唱的歌
This gentleman's song...
热情奔放、创意无限
...is very creative and sincere.
多谢
Thank you!
不用客气
You're welcome!
燃点起我酱爆心中的一团火
I also love to sing.
我酱爆感觉到, 在这个时刻
When I'm inspired I feel so passionate...
要爆了
...I could explode.
我猪肉佬何尝不想成为一个伟大的舞蹈家
My dream is to become a great choreographer.
好
Let's go!
你是不是吃饱了撑的?
Have you lost your mind?
站直!  手放下!  脖子伸直
Stand straight! Put your hands down! Get to work!
你们全都神经病
Lunatics!
在这里跳什么舞?
What's going on here?
死丫头!  真没用
I never should have gone...
我只不过去做一下面膜
...for a facial...
你就把这里搞得乱七八糟,  真是贱骨头
...and left the place in your hands!
你这臭要饭的过来干什么?
What do you want?
你骂人不要骂得那么凶
Relax. We were just having fun.
我是来买馒头的
I'm here for the buns.
老板娘,  馒头好了没有?
Is my steamed bread ready?
好了…  等一下
Okay! Just a minute! Did that bum pay?
那个臭要饭的有没有给钱?
Did the guy pay for the steamed bread?
给了
He did.
这脏了吧唧什么东西?  还不给我扔了
What's this dirty stuff? Throw it away!
大师兄
First Big Brother!
大师兄…
行了…
It's okay!
你们自觉一点,  干活好不好?
Keep working. Clean it up, please!
大师兄,  你身体不舒服吗?
Are you sick, First Big Brother?
昨晚喝多了,  头好疼
I've a headache. I got drunk last night.
你又想干嘛?
Anyway, what do you want?
我想告诉你,  我醒了
I want to let you know I awakened already.
- 你醒了?     - 醒了
- Truly? You awakened.     - I awakened.
我终于领悟到
I finally understood.
如果要将少林功夫发扬到全世界
If I want to develop Shaolin kung fu to the world,
是要讲包装的
I should package it into a new and modern form.
什么包装?
What's kind of packaging?
唱歌
Singing!
今天我的糟遇说出来你也不信
You won't believe what I see today.
- 我经过一间馒头店…     - 你不要说了
- I see a steamed bread shop...     - Stop bothering me!
不是呀!  少林功夫加唱歌跳舞
But, what do you think if I combine Shaolin kung fu...
你说有没有搞头?
...with singing and dancing?
没搞头
Don't think about that!
你没做,  怎么知道没搞头?
How can you give anything up if you never try it?
你不要做了
Stop thinking about that!
我劝你要脚踏实地做人嘛!
I've already advised you to live in a down-to-earth manner.
这里有份洗厕所的工作先做着
There's a vacancy for cleaning toilet. It should be good for you...
你就别做梦了
...to take it rather than to dream anything.
做人如果没梦想,  跟咸鱼有什么分别?
If we don't have any dream in life, we'll look like a salt fish.
你鞋子都没有,  不就是咸鱼一条
You see, you're a real salt fish without a pair of shoes!
还学人家讲理想?
How can you talk about dream?
话不能这么讲
Oh, no!
我心中的一团火是不会熄的
My firing-hearted is not easy to blow out!
那就把它吹熄了,  不熄?
Why not? Just blow it out!
熄了可再点着它
But I can light it up again!
够啦!
Enough, already!
我有我的生活,  你点你的火
We both have our own lives.
总之你不要再烦我了
Please don't bother me!
我要养家糊口呀!  大哥
I should work to support my family.
当年你苦练铁头功
You mean you are willing to give your Iron Head up.
你就忍心这么眼巴巴的荒废了?
Did you forget how much effort you made for it?
错
You're wrong!
这十几年来我的铁头功
I don't give it up...
从来没有一天荒废过
...even one day!
阿飞
Fei!
老板
Boss!
妈了个巴子
Damn it!
明天跳舞的妞发脾气全跑啦!
The dancers quitted the show already.
你还在闲聊?
How can you stick to here and do nothing for that?
不是,  我想到一个好主意
No! I have a great idea.
什么主意?
What's that?
就是…少林功夫加唱歌跳舞
Combining Shaolin kung fu with singing and dancing.
什么少林功夫?
What's kind of Shaolin kung fu?
看那边
Look at this!
就一个人?  有什么看头
It's no way for sole.
一个就够了
He's good enough.
不行!  加上你吧!
No! How about you?
我?
Me?
妈了个巴子
Shit!
你会铁头功嘛!
How about your Iron Head?
明晚给我好好干,  不然我先干了你
If you don't do it well, I'll kill you tomorrow.
是
Yes.
大师兄,  多谢你
First Big Brother, thank you!
少林功夫好
Shaolin kung fu is great!
真的好
Really great!
少林功夫棒
Shaolin kung fu is wonderful!
真的棒
Wonderful!
我是铁头功
I'm Iron Head.
无敌铁头功
Iron Head.
你是金刚腿
You're Mighty Steel Leg.
我是金刚腿
I'm Mighty Steel Leg.
认真点
Be serious!
少林功夫好
Shaolin kung fu is great!
真是好
Really great!
少林功夫好
Shaolin kung fu is great!
太棒了
Really great!
少林功夫带劲
Shaolin kung fu is wonderful!
顶呱呱
Wonderful!
我是金刚腿
I'm Mighty Steel Leg!
金刚腿
Mighty Steel Leg!
他是铁头功
He's Iron Head!
哇你的头
Damn it!
你们唱什么?  鬼哭狼嚎似的
What are you singing about? Your voice seems howling.
歌词乱七八糟的
The lyric is disgusting.
我…一句都听不明白
I even can't understand one sentence of this.
就是,  歌词谁写的?
Yes, of course. Who wrote this lyric?
- 谁写的?     - 说
- Who did?     - Who did?
其实,  创作这东西是很主观的
Creative work is highly subjective,
不过你们的批评,  我是一定会跟进的
but I must follow up your criticism.
况且唱歌只不过是前奏而已
Singing is just the beginning of the show,
高潮就是少林的大力金刚腿和铁头功
the climax is the performance of Mighty Steel Leg and Iron Head!
铁头功是吧?
Iron Head?
早说了,  这歌词不行嘛!
I had already told you that you wrote the bad lyric.
我不是铁头功,  他才是
I'm not Iron Head. He's...
铁头功是吧?
Iron Head?
- 都说…     - 铁头功是吧?
- I said...     - Iron Head?
金刚腿
Mighty Steel Leg!
他才是金刚腿呀!
He's Mighty Steel Leg!
你还说金刚腿?
You still say Mighty Steel Leg?
打死你
Killing you!
狗屁金刚腿
Mighty Steel Leg!
我才是金刚腿
I'm the real Mighty Steel Leg!
铁头功是吧?
Iron Head?
你听不懂中国话,  那个才是…
Don't you know Chinese? He's the real...
铁头功是吧?
Iron Head?
你打上瘾了?
You're so stubborn!
铁…
Iron...
干嘛?  想还手?
Do you want to fight back against me?
多谢啦…
Thank you so much!
欢乐的时光过得特别快
Happy hour is going fast.
又到时候讲拜拜
It's time for us to say goodbye right now.
大家先来听首歌,  音乐
Let's listen to music!
你妈的!  还装蒜?
You crazy guys!
还在这儿死撑?
Let's see if you can take more!
多谢了…
Thank you!
瘸你妈的
Bullshit!
干嘛?
What?
走!  没什么好看的
Go! Nothing interested!
你没打够,  还想再打?
Do you still want to fight with us?
我答应过师父不打架的
I promised my Shaolin master I wouldn't use kung fu to fight with anyone.
大哥,  这家伙脑部震荡过度呀!
This guy is crazy.
但是你们一定要道歉
But all you guys should apologize!
道歉?
Apologize?
我打你应该,  不打你悲哀
I don't think it's my problem. It's all yours guy's fault!
不要动!  你说过不打架的
Don't move! You said you would not use kung fu to hit anyone.
我不是来打架,  我是来踢球的
I'm not coming for fighting. I'm coming for playing soccer.
我干你的…
Shit!
用不着这么夸张吧?
You don't need to be so exaggerated!
干什么?
What?
不好意思呀!  大哥,  对不起
I'm so sorry!
你有带钱在身上吗?
Do you have some coins right now?
有
Yes.
三毛
Thirty cents.
这算不算抢劫?
Are you grabbing my money?
算,  你学过螳螂拳吗?
Yes, I am. Did you learn Tong Long Fist?
研究过
I did.
那就不要再侮辱少林武功
Don't insult Shaolin kung fu anymore!
介不介意把裤子拉高点?
Would you let me...
让我看看你的腿
...take a look of your leg?
我心情不太好,  要拉你自己拉
I'm not in the mood. Go ahead!
真是天生神力
Cool! It's the real, original kung fu.
好一条夺命香鸡腿
A great killer silm leg.
是少林的大力金刚腿
It's Shaolin Mighty Steel Leg!
功夫真的可以用来踢球吗?
Is it possible using kung fu to play soccer?
功夫踢球有搞头吗?
Truly?
有搞头
Yes, of course!
对呀!
Yeah!
功夫踢球好主意
It's a great idea of using kung fu to play soccer.
为什么我一直没想到呢?
Why did I ever think about that?
你不是那个瘸子?
Are you the lame?
我不是瘸子那么简单
I'm not just the lame,
我还是当年叱吒球坛的黄金右脚
I'm the ex-soccer player, Golden Leg.
现在是足球教练
Today, I'm a soccer coach.
那正好,  你教我踢球
It's great! You should teach me playing soccer.
等一下
Hold on.
还等什么?  是你说有搞头的
No! You told me I could use kung fu to play soccer.
没错,  那也要给我点时间想一想
But I need time to consider!
已经没时间了
I've no time to think anymore!
太阳都下山啦!  有搞头就赶快做
It's sunset already!
时间是不等人的
Time doesn't wait for anyone!
那也要准备一下嘛!
But we still need to prepare!
我已经准备好啦!  还差什么?
I'm ready! What do I need?
起码要有一对球鞋嘛!
At least a pair of shoes!
你现在有钱赎回你的破鞋了?
Do you have money to get your sneakers back?
钱还没有,  但是…
No. But...
扔掉了
I threw them away.
扔掉了?
Oh, my god!
当然,  你的破鞋已经破得没法穿了
Your sneakers were broken. They're well worn.
- 破是破,  但是我…     - 你快走吧!
- Yes, they were broken. But I...     - Go home!
等一下老板娘出来,  又要骂人了
My boss will shout at you when she comes back and sees you.
破的鞋没有了
It's impossible to get the broken one back.
补好的有一双,  你要不要?
There is a repaired one. Do you want to have it?
大师兄,  你怎么了?
First Big Brother, what are you doing?
大师兄,  你没事吧?
First Big Brother, are you okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
你又想怎样?
What do you want?
我终于想到个妙计
I finally got a good idea...
可以将少林武功更加发扬光大
...to develop Shaolin kung fu.
就是踢球
This's playing soccer!
你放我一条生路吧!
Please let me go!
你已害我被人打,  还被解雇了
You had already got me into trouble. I was fired.
现在我要洗厕所赔钱
Now, I work at rest room to pay for my boss's loss.
所以我是来打救你的
So I come here to help you.
不用了!  你还打救得不够?
No! Absolutely not!
你别逼我,  是不是…
If you force me anymore,
想我全家跳楼死在你面前?
my whole family will commit suicide in front of you.
死是不能解决问题的
Committing suicide is not a good way to solve any problems.
你勇敢一点
Be brave!
你的志气跑哪去了?
Don't be so silly!
就当我没志气!  就当我烂泥扶不上墙
I'm a loser!
拜托你不要再找我
Please don't come here anymore!
你要找,  找其他师兄弟吧!
If you still want to form a soccer team, you can call the other Brothers.
拜托你了,  求求你不要再烦我…
Please, don't bother me!
我求求你啦!
I beg you!
铁头功
Iron Head.
四师兄,  早
Good morning, Fourth Big Brother!
星哥,  早
Good morning, Sing!
好久不见,  有什么好关照?
How are you?
给你介绍位猛男,  这位是…
Let me introduce a great guy to you! He's...
喂!  怎么称呼?
Nice to meet you!
叫我阿锋行啦!
This is Fung.
锋哥是吧?  财经界有谁不认识锋哥
I know, Fung is so famous in the stock exchange market.
你看他一身的IT造型
You see! He has a great I.T. Look.
锋哥是位足球教练
Fung is a soccer coach.
足球教练是吧?
Soccer coach!
足球界有谁不认识锋哥的?
Everyone knows that Fung is the most...
我从小就看锋哥踢球了
...famous figure in the soccer field.
你是用两只脚踢球,  对吧?
Do you use your legs to play soccer?
我没乱盖吧!  有什么好关照?
You see! I'm right. Actually, do you have any job?
打算找你组队踢球
I want you to join into my soccer team.
真的找我踢球?
Playing soccer?
我半年没做事了,  你找我踢球?
I've no job for six months. How can you ask me to play soccer?
不是,  你当年的鬼影擒拿手
If you can use your Empty Hand...
如果拿来当守门员的话…
...to be the goalkeeper...
鬼屁影擒拿手?  多年前的事了
What's Empty Hand? It's many years ago.
师父死了多久我都不记得了
You know, I even forgot when our Master died.
你听我说
Please listen to me!
我们这次是参加两年一度的超级杯
We're going to sign up the National Soccer Tournament.
赢了有一百万奖金呀!
The prize is one million dollars.
是吗?  所以我一直说你最精明能干
Really? So I say you're the smartest one.
风生水起、西装革履,  你看你帅的
You see! You're dressed up.
当年师父叫我们将少林功夫发扬光大
Many years ago, our Master ordered us to develop Shaolin kung fu.
现在居然让你们两混球发扬到足球上
Now, you guys get this great idea of using Shaolin kung fu...
真是有见地
...to play soccer.
你看看
You see!
当年我们几师兄弟的合照
This's the group picture of our Master and Brothers.
我一直摆在枕头下面
I always keep it under my pillow.
你就知道我是什么…
You should know what I mean.
好啊!  我们坐下来慢慢谈什么…
Great! Let's sit down to talk about what you mean.
我有空找你们,  记得叫我
I'll call you if I've time. Remember, please leave a room for me.
我没空跟你说话
I really don't have time to talk to you.
几个客人在等我,  还要盯着股市
Some clients waiting for me, I should keep my eyes on the stock exchange market.
一秒钟几十万上下呢!
You know, my trading is more than hundreds thousand dollars each.
喂!  现在什么价位?
Hello! What's the price right now?
碰巧今天司机放大假
Today, my driver is on leave.
碰巧今天又把车借给人家了
I just lend my car to my friend,
碰巧刚把钱包留在公司
and left my wallet in my office.
今天我请不了你吃饭啦!
I'm sorry! I don't have time to have lunch with you guys.
我真的很忙呀!
I'm really busy!
嘀…  车来了呀!
Get away!
考虑一下,  三师兄
Third Big Brother, think about it!
你当年的金钟罩铁布衫
If you can use Iron Shirt...
如果用来踢后卫…
...to be the back...
你…你还提金钟罩铁布衫?
What's Iron Shirt?
你看看,  满天都是飞机
You see! There are full of planes in the sky.
满街都是电脑
There are full of computer on the street.
现在什么世界了?  你醒醒吧!
It's the 21 st century. Please don't live in your daydream!
所以我打算用武功配合足球搞新组合
So I think it's a good idea of combining kung fu with soccer together.
是呀!  奖金很吸引人的
It's true! The prize is a great deal of money.
我靠!  你当我什么?
For Chirst sake! You think I'm...
我一秒钟几十万上下
My trading is hundreds thousand dollars each.
无缘无故跟你们几个废物去踢球
It's absolutely no way to give my trading up and to play soccer with you guys.
不好意思,  你知道我这个人就这么直
I'm sorry. You know, I'm so direct.
还要无缘无故跟你这死瘸子参加比赛
It's impossible to give my trading up and to sign up any soccer games with you lame.
请你原谅我是这么直
Forgive me. I'm a honest guy.
最后还要无缘无故的赢了比赛
Finally, it's also impossible for me to win the fucking soccer game.
或然率是低过零呀!
Truly, the probability of winning is 0%.
你说的这个或然轮嘛!
Probabi...
你才轮!  是或然率呀!
Probability!
简单来说,  就是…
Okay...
要不就是公,  要不就是字
It should be head or tail.
永远没有中间的
We'll never get the middle.
中间的或然率就是零
So the probability is 0%.
让我来试试看
Let me try!
你给我走
Get away!
我约了人在大酒店吃午饭
I've an appointment with my client at coffee shop.
我很忙啊!
I'm very busy!
我们俩请你吃碗杂碎面再谈好了
We can serve you to have noodle at stalling store.
我靠!  我一秒钟几十万
Bullshit! My trading is hundreds thousands dollars each.
跟你们吃杂碎面?
How can I go to have noodle with you guys?
这位就是我六师弟,  绰号"轻功水上飘"
He's my Sixth Small Brother, Weight Vest.
这位是著名足球教练—锋哥
This is the famous soccer coach, Fung.
锋哥,  你好
Fung, how are you?
什么飘?
What's Vest?
轻功水上飘
Weight Vest.
轻先生,  你好
Nice to meet you! Mr.Vest.
师兄,  你要去踢球吗?
Fifth Big Brother, are you thinking about playing soccer?
是呀!
Yes.
如果加上你身轻如燕水上飘坐阵
If you can use Shaolin kung fu, Weight Vest to be the forward with me.
我们上中二路的攻击可说是毫无破绽
Our attack should be flawless.
- 你真的这么肯定?     - 是
- Do you have confidence of this?     - Of course.
好,  请问有没有特效减肥药?
Great! Is there any pills for diet?
没用的
It's useless.
我是感冒菌入脑下垂,  没得减了
Since the virus get into the cerebellum, it's no way for me to loose any bounds.
自从师父去世之后,  我就这么胖
After I became like this, I'm not only unable to use Shaolin kung fu,
现在别说轻功了,  想走快点都不行
Weight Vest, but to walk quickly.
胖是胖了点,  不过问题不大
Yes, you're a little bit fat, but it's not so important.
算啦!
Forget it!
你看看我以前的样子
You see, it was my picture!
自从变成这样子
Since I've become like this,
连妞都泡不到
I even can't date a girl.
这种心情你们不会明白的
You don't understand that.
我明白,  我又何尝不是呢?
I do. I also can't date a girl!
不是呀!
Really?
报纸杂志说你很多女朋友
There has been much gossip about your girls on newspaper and magazine?
什么报纸杂志?
What's kind of newspaper and magazine?
对不起,  我又说错话了
Oh! I'm sorry!
自从有了这个病之后,  我经常失控
Since I've this disease, I can't control myself.
你不用管我,  你走吧!
I'm sorry. Please leave me alone!
师弟
Small Brother!
给自己点信心,  你行的
You should have confidence! You can do it!
现在大家都叫我猪肥膘
Now, everyone calls me Lazy Pig.
只有你叫我师弟
You know, you're the only one who call me Small Brother.
谢谢
Thank you!
猪肥膘,  帮我把上面红色厕纸拿下来
Lazy Pig, please help me to pick the red loaf of tissue.
是红色那卷
The red one!
踢球?
Playing soccer?
是呀!  二师兄
Yes, Second Big Brother!
你当年的旋风地堂腿如果用来做后卫
If you can use Hooking Leg to be the back,
我敢肯定…
I believe...
毫无破绽嘛!
The defense is none of flaw!
没错
Absolutely!
看我现在这德性,  还是旋风地堂腿吗?
Don't you think I still can use Hooking Leg?
生疏一点点没关系
Just need some practice.
只要有斗志,  武功一定会回来的
If you trust yourself, you will get your Hooking Leg back.
是吗?
Really?
不过前阵子我看见你还在洗马桶
I just saw you collecting excrement and urine recently.
怎么好好的又转做洗碗呢?
Why did you change your job to wash dishes?
为什么?
Why?
这个问题我也想问,  我也不明白
Why is this your question? I don't understand, too.
为什么我老爸不是李嘉诚?
Why isn't my dad the richest guy, Lee Ka Sing?
为什么我长得这么帅?  但要掉头发
Why am I going blad, even though I'm so handsome?
你们俩长这么丑,  就不掉头发
You guys are not going blad, but you're so ugly.
为什么人家小时候有书读?
Why could the other guys go to school when they were young?
而我小时候就要被我老爸
But I was forced to study the Shaolin kung fu,
逼我练什么烂鬼武功?
and then became a cleaner to wash dishes,
练到现在洗马桶、洗碗
to collect excrement and urine?
二师兄,  你冷静一点
Calm down! Second Big Brother.
其实命运是掌握在自己手中的
If you're brave enough, you can control your fate.
冷静?  如果不够冷静
Calm down? If I didn't calm down,
我一刀砍死你们两个王八旦了
I would kill you guys!
冷静?
Calm down?
妈个巴子!  这么有空坐着
Why have you just sat here?
闻到臭不臭呀?
Didn't you smell anything disgusting?
一会回来还有臭味,  你给我舔干净
If there's disgusting smell when I come back, you will clean it with your tongue!
这个地方不错呀!
Your apartment is great!
五脏俱全呢!
It's well furnished.
想不到你这个垃圾佬
I can't imagine you work as the cleaner at downstairs,
居然可以在五十九楼天台住阁楼
but live in the Penhouse on the 59th floor.
好有生活品味呀!
You've good taste!
现在这种单位很抢手的
This kind of apartment is so popular.
我找了很久都找不到
I can't even get one.
就是这个冷气槽有点吵
The trough is okay.
没关系…
Just little bit noisy.
在你这儿多隔个房间行不行?
Would you mind if I move here?
算啦!
Forget it!
你那些师兄弟没个像样的
Your Brothers are not good.
不来就算啦!  再找其他人吧!
We can find the others to join our team.
都怪我不好,  说不动他们
It was all my fault. I couldn't persuade them.
不要这么说了
It's okay.
你这么信任我这个瘸子
You know, I'm so glad that you trust me.
我很感谢你
Thank you.
我会在最短的时间里
I'll use the shortest period of time to train all you guys...
将你们训练成为足球员
...to be the professional soccer players.
所以你们要严肃认真、团结向上
So you should be serious and mutually support each other.
明白啦!
I understand!
踢球
Let's go!
你听我说好不好?
Please listen to me!
你站在我的立场,  你会怎么样?
What would you do if you stand on my position?
就是嘛!
Yes, of course.
等等,  我有电话进来
I've a call. Hold on a second.
球掉下来啦!
The soccer is coming back!
你终于下来了吗?
Oh! Are you willing to come back finally?
让我们等了一个多小时
You let us wait for an hour, wait for an hour!
干什么呀?
What are you doing?
踢球
Playing soccer!
球在那边呀!
The soccer is over there!
你,  站过来
You, come here!
你在这儿踢球给我看看
Let me see you kick the soccer here.
可是球在那边
The soccer is over there.
就是嘛!  你也知道球在那边
Yes. The soccer is over there!
你连球都没拿到,  踢什么呀?
You can't even get the soccer. How can you kick it from here?
其实踢球不外乎四个基本:
Actually, there are four basic skills of playing soccer:
传、停、带、射
Pass, stop, hold and kick.
- 我明白     - 你别动
- I understand!     - Don't move!
你们要从基本做起
Okay. Start from the beginning.
你的
Yours.
控制住
Hold it!
集中精神
Watch out!
交…  带球
Concentrate!
你要走位才行呀!
Come on! Move!
这些假动作可以再假点
Yes... you can do more dummies.
你就差不多了,  挺假的
Almost fine. It seems a great dummy.
假点,  再假点
Do more dummies.
教练,  为什么不让我练球?
Fung, why can't I take a part of training?
你的脚力太大
Even though your leg is so strong,
因为你做不到收放自如
you can't control it freely.
每次都把球踢上天
How about if you kick the soccer into the sky...
万一把飞机打下来你赔得起吗?
...and then hit a plane? Can you pay for it?
- 赔不起     - 就是嘛!
- No.     - So...
肥仔聪,  借你的鸡蛋用用
Sixth Small Brother! I borrow your eggs!
什么?
What?
你能将鸡蛋像控球那样控好再说吧!
If you can control the egg freely in the air, you can play soccer.
- 好呀!  来     - 来
- No problem!     - Okay!
有难度的
Go ahead. It's not easy.
靠!  算了吧!  六师弟
Sixth Small Brother, forget it!
我的蛋…
Oh, my god! My egg!
总有一天,  我把蛋还给你的
I must return it to you in the future!
还你的头
No way!
把蛋还给我
Give it back to me!
不要分心,  继续
Concentrate...
蛋呀!
My egg!
前面,  对…
Yes! Yes!
很好…
接着
Yours!
对…
Right...
很好…
Good...
好!  去
Yes! Go!
防守的要钉紧一点
Mark that one! Watch out!
不能让人射球
How can you let him to kick the soccer?
射的那个用点力呀!
Kick it!
我也挡到啦!
Come on!
真厉害
It's great!
他一个人踢就行了
He can just play it by himself.
足球,  不是一个人就可以踢的
No! It's teamwork. It's no way just for one to play soccer.
比赛三十分钟,  中场没休息
The game is 30 minutes. There is no break.
一切依足国际球例
We'll follow the international rules.
我做球证,  大家没意见吧?
I'm the referee. Do you have any questions?
不要傻了,  当年人称黄金右脚的锋哥
Don't be silly? You know, how great you Golden Leg plays as referee...
今天带些年青人来跟我们踢场友谊赛
...and leads a young soccer team to play with us.
你还做球证,  是我们的荣幸
We should be glad about that!
大家叫锋哥
This's Fung!
锋哥
Fung!
好了…
Okay...
这个年青人之前和你的队员有点冲撞
This guy has some struggles with your team players.
所以打算踢一场球赛,  切磋一下球技
Now, this game is an exchange of our skills of playing soccer.
以前的恩怨就一笔勾消吧!
It is used to solve this conflict.
他们很有诚意的
You see! They play sincerely.
从他们整齐的制服、友善的眼神
From their tidy uniform and friendly face,
我完全感受到那份诚意和体育精神
I can deeply feel their sincerity and the spirit of physical culture.
多谢
Thank you!
大家不要紧张
Calm down.
我本身是一个汽车维修员
I'm a car repairer.
这个扳子是我用来上螺丝用的
This crescent wrench is used to hold for screwing.
很合理吧?
Does it make sense?
是呀…
Yes, of course.
正如我刚才所说
I explained it already.
我身为一个汽车维修员
Because I'm a car repairer,
有个锤子在身边也很合逻辑
it's all right for me to have a hammer.
行了…  你们球队的作风
Okay. Your team's style...
在业余界是很出名的
...is very famous in the amateur soccer field.
我完全明白
I understand.
那些只是虚名而已
It's just the undeserved reputation.
就好像浮云一样
Seems the cloud in the sky...
好了…  大伙小心点
Okay. Anyway, take care of yourselves.
大家握握手
Shake hand, please!
好球
Great!
救命…
Help!
三师兄
Third Big Brother!
呼叫基地,  突然间受到密集火力攻击
Calling the military base, we were just suffered the fierce attack.
要求马上增援…
Ask for reinforcement!
要求马上增援
起来
Stand up.
Stand up!
快点起来
Stand up quickly!
你干什么?
What are you doing?
他们赖皮呀!  教练
Coach, they are lawless.
快点吹哨呀!
Why didn't you stop them?
我是球证,  我不吹
I'm the referee. I don't stop them.
那是什么意思?  要我们去送死吗?
What's the meaning of this? Do you want us to scarifice?
你,  出场
You! Out!
你疯啦!
Are you nuts?
这是一个考验
This is a test.
如果他们连这一关都过不了
If you guys can't pass it,
以后就不要再说踢球啦!
it's no way to play soccer anymore!
这不过是踢球,  你以为打仗吗?
We're just playing soccer. We're not fighting in a battle.
真正的比赛,  就是打仗
The real soccer game is a battle.
投降啦…
Surrender!
I surrender!
我投降啦!
你敢来找我比赛
If you were brave enough to ask me playing soccer,
现在还没进球你就想撤退
why did you surrender?
这不是惹我发火吗?
Do you play and loose with me?
我不行了,  我的腰快断了
I can't stand for it anymore. My bone seems broken.
我求你可怜可怜我
I'm the pitiful creature!
让我去看医生
Please let me go to see a doctor!
戴头上
Put it onto your head!
几十岁的人,  你看你多贱
You see. You look like a dog.
你没尊严?
Do you have any self-respect?
我不想看见你
I don't want to see you.
快点戴上它,  然后去看医生
Put it onto your head quickly and go to see a doctor.
我是很贱,  我没尊严,  拿来
Yes, I'm a dog. I don't have any self-respect.
大师兄回来了
First Big Brother is coming back.
你说什么?
What?
我感觉到,  全都回来了
I've a feeling that they are back.
- 还有没有家伙?     - 没有
- Do we still have any weapons?     - No more!
干掉他们
The final attack!
这都不进
Oh, my God! I couldn't get it.
救命啊!
Help!
全靠你,  我们才有发挥的机会
Thank you! You make us to get our kung fu back.
欢迎各位师兄弟归位
Thanks for coming back!
谢谢你
Thank you!
你们不用客气
Don't be like this.
我要谢谢你们大家
I'm the real one who needs to thank for all you guys.
这次我发财啦!  多谢…
Oh, my God! I'm going to be rich! Thank you!
我们认输了,  求求给次机会
We're failed. Please give us an opportunity...
让我们加入你的球队
...to join into your team!
求求你啦…
Please!
给次机会…
Please, give us a chance.
这么惊人的爆炸力
It's a pretty big exploration.
魔鬼队拿世界冠军是早晚的事
The Evil Team'll be the champion in the world.
你说谁?
Who?
死瘸子?
The lame?
- 为什么不可以?     - 不好意思,  先生
- Why not?     - I'm sorry.
小妹妹,  我踢球时你还没出生呢!
I've already played soccer for many years,
- 什么不好意思?     - 我们负责人不在
- you want to stop me?     - The person in charge is not here now.
黄金右脚
Golden Leg!
你又在这里呀?
What are you doing?
- 雄哥     - 雄哥,  他…
- Hung!     - Hung, he...
行了…
Okay...
雄哥,  我想带我的球队来参赛
Hung, my team wants to sign it up for the soccer game!
公开赛嘛!  人人都有权参赛的
It's an open competition, everyone has the right to sign up.
不是人人都有权
You're wrong.
我是委员会主席
I'm the chairman.
我说有权,  你才有权
I've the right to decide who can sign it up.
- 明白吗?     - 明白
- Do you understand?     - Yes.
你那队是什么队?
What's the name of your team?
来,  过来…
Come on!
叫雄哥
This is Hung.
雄哥…
Hung!
这队简直是极品啊!
This is a rare soccer team!
我真的很想看看
I really want to watch them playing soccer.
什么名堂?
What's the name again?
这队叫少林足…
This is Shaolin...
随便…
OK...
你快去报名,  我真的很想见识一下
Go and sign it up quickly. I really want to watch them.
有没有报名费?  我来付
If you need, I can pay for your application fee.
多谢…
Thank you!
无所谓,  我和你是兄弟嘛!  死瘸子
It's okay! You guy, the lame, is my friendly brother.
我的鞋又有点脏了
My shoe is dirty again.
白色容易脏
White color is easy to get dirty.
那应该怎么办呢?
So...
我帮你擦…
I help you to clean it up!
清洁我拿手,  让我来
I'm good at cleaning. Let me try!
粗活我来…
This is my duty!
让我来…
Hey! Let me try!
嗨!
Hi!
你干嘛?
What are you doing?
你是谁?
Who are you?
你要带我去哪?
Where do we go?
你干嘛不讲话?  我回去了
Why are you so quiet? I need to go home.
怎么这么久?
I'm waiting for a long time.
对不起,  等一下就好,  很快
I'm sorry. Please, wait a moment.
试试看
Try this.
不…  我是看用什么材料做的
No. I just want to see the quality of it.
那摸摸看
Touch it.
会把它弄脏的
I'll make it dirty.
- 没关系,  来     - 不…
- No problem. Go ahead.     - No...
- 摸吧!  来     - 不用了
- Touch it.     - No.
- 怎么样?     - 挺滑的
- How about that?     - So smooth.
- 我送给你     - 摸了就可以了
- I promise I'll buy one for you.     - I touched it already. It's enough.
我告诉你,  我明天要去踢足球了
Tomorrow, I'll go to play soccer.
是吗?
Really?
我一定会红透半边天的
I must become a famous star player.
但如果当时没有你帮我把这双鞋补好
But if you didn't help me to repair them.
可能我就不会踢球了
I would never play soccer.
你对我多重要,  你知道吗?
You know, you're so important to me.
你喜欢什么全告诉我
Tell me what you want.
我很快就可以送给你了
I can pay for you very soon.
你要是红了,  就送我一双球鞋吧!
If you become rich and famous, please buy me sneakers.
这个太没问题了吧!
No problem!
但是我觉得你也应该有点自信
But you should have confidence.
其实你很漂亮的,  武功又高强
Actually, you're a beautiful girl good at kung fu.
简直是完美呀!
You know, you are perfect.
但是你不要老把头发挡住自己嘛!
You can't let your hair down and cover your face like this.
来…
Come on.
- 来吧!  看着我…     - 不要…
- Come on. Look at me.     - No...
看着我…
Look at me!
你看,  多漂亮
So beautiful!
真的吗?
Really?
是啊!
Yes, of course.
是苍蝇吗?
Is it fly?
是,  还没打到
Yes. But I didn't catch it.
打到了吗?
Did you catch it already?
打到了
I did.
对不起,  把你的手都弄脏了
I'm sorry. I make your hand dirty.
没事
No problem.
你是最漂亮的,  知道吗?
You know, you're the most beautiful girl.
你知道吗?
Do you know that?
知道,  知道了
Yes. I do.
我真的很感谢你呀!
Thank you! Thanks so much!
你知道吗?
Do you know?
你去哪啦?
Where you go?
你答应帮我洗地,  才让你带妞来威风
I let you bring a girl here because you promised me to clean the store.
别看那么久,  背黑锅了,  快干活
Hurry up! If you haven't finished the work on time, I'll be in trouble.
你先走吧!  我再找你
Go home. I'll call you later.
好吧?
Okay?
要有自信,  你是最好的,  知道吗?
Remember! You should have confidence. You're the best.
我喜欢你的衣服呀!
I like your shirt.
我喜欢你的袜子
I like your socks, too.
- 不如我们交换穿     - 好…
- Let's exchange to wear.     - Good...
别玩啦!  臭小子,  没见过大场面吗?
Hey, guys! Didn't you ever see this occasion?
放松点,  就像平时练球一样就行了
Just play as usual as training.
一会儿会有很多观众和记者
There'll be hundreds of reporters and audiences outside.
对记者,  记着要笑
You guys should keep smile...
让他们给我们拍照
...and let the reporters take pictures with us.
和群众热情打招呼,  多谢大家的支持
You also need to say hi and thank for the audience's support.
多谢…
Thank you!
多谢
多谢你们的支持
Thanks for your support!
多谢
Thank you!
是扫地的
They're just cleaners.
扫地的不是观众吗?
Cleaner is also the audience.
多谢你们
Thank you!
不要吵啦!
Shut up!
这场子这么小?  还空空的,  你不是说…
This auditorium is so small and empty. You said...
外围赛是这样的啦!
This is just the first round.
所以我们要努力,  踢入决赛
So we should play well and get into the finals.
- 好!  踢入决赛     - 不要吵啦!
- Great! Get into the finals!     - Shut up!
少林足球队
Shaolin Team?
看这个…
Look at this guy!
看那个…
Look at that guy!
干什么?
What happened?
不能抽烟?
No smoking here?
干什么?
What happened?
没理由,  是幻觉
It's impossible! Just an illusion!
你干什么?
What are you doing?
不用怕,  全是幻觉
It's okay, just an illusion.
看来我们豆腐金刚队要出真功夫了
I think we should show off our real power.
好
Great!
你又干什么?
What's wrong?
你们不要这样,  我想踢球啊!
Please don't play like this! I really want to play soccer!
雄哥,  电话
Hung, it's your call.
都是幻觉,  吓不倒我
I'm not scared. It's just an illusion.
什么?  四十比零?
What? Forty versus zero?
好棒啊!
Yeah!
进吧!  铁头功啊!
Got a goal! Iron Head!
没错,  我们学的是少林武功
Yes, we use Shaolin kung fu to play soccer.
少林武功的确是棒
So kung fu is great, wonderful!
- 我们很低调的…     - 还有
- We lie low...     - And...
我要多谢我的父母和师父
I want to thanks for my parents and my Shaolin master.
虽然他们已经过身了
Even though they passed away already.
我还要多谢我的好朋友—阿梅
I want to thanks for my good friend, Mui.
阿梅…  是我呀!  阿梅
Mui... How are you?
你怎么样?  吃了饭没有?
Did you have your dinner already?
靓女,  找我呀?
Hi! Can I help?
我想…
I want...
不用说了,  放心交给我吧!
I understand. Let me take care of you!
可不可以现场给我们观众表演一下?
Would you mind show us your kung fu?
可以…  肥仔聪
Yes, of course, Sixth Small Brother.
一、二、三
1, 2, 3!
好
Great!
能不能再来一次?
Can you show us one more?
- 再来一次     - 可以大师兄,  来…
- Sure!     - Big Brother, one more please.
慢点…  不用急
Take it easy!
各位师兄弟,  从今天开始
My Brothers,
我们要跟这堆烂鞋讲拜拜
today we say bye with our old sneakers.
你们不要乱扔东西好不好?
Don't throw anything here!
对不起…
Sorry...
阿梅?
Mui?
干嘛?
What's up?
你今天好精灵呀!
You look great tonight.
少许吧!
Just a little.
不少了,  好厉害呀!
It's a big difference. You're so heavily made up.
好看吗?
So you think I look nice?
告诉你一个好消息
I have big news for you.
我们赢了球赛,  你知道吗?
We won the soccer match.
我知道,  在电视上都看到你们了
I know. I saw you guys on TV.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
送给你
This is for you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我先介绍我的朋友给你,  来…
Let me introduce you to my friends.
哗!  好厉害
Nice outfit.
给你们介绍一个朋友
Hey, let me introduce you guys to a new friend.
你是人还是鬼?
Is she a ghost?
她是自己人来的
This is my friend.
- 嫂子是吧?     - 不是
- Girlfriend?     - No.
我常跟你们说做太极馒头的阿梅呀!
This is Mui, the Tai Chi Master I told you guys about.
就是她
Oh, nice to meet you.
嫂子是极品呀!
Your girlfriend is quite unique.
她真是极品呀!
Yes.
看得出来
That's great.
整块床板放在肩上,  我从来没见过
I've never seen shoulder pads so big.
我花两个晚上才做两块
I've decided to start a new trend.
两块呀?
See? It's fashionable.
这么晚了,  你不要把嫂子带出来嘛!
Don't walk around at night.
把人家都吓死了
It's quite scary.
不怕
It's okay.
做场法事,  我想没事吧!
People will get used to it soon.
稳当点,  把她绑起来扔下海算了
It will work pretty well in football.
你以后不吃鱼了?
You want to borrow them?
你们不要取笑,  她是女孩子呀!
Stop it. It's not proper to talk to a lady like this.
没关系…  随便…
It's okay, I can take it.
她虽然是女孩子,  但挺能玩的
Although she's a girl, she has a great sense of humor.
阿梅,  摆个性感姿势给大家看看
Mui, show us a sexy pose.
还有没有?
Give us a kiss.
- 干嘛?     - 别碰我
- What's wrong?     - Don't touch me.
生气了?
Are you mad?
没生气
No, I'm not mad.
那你…
Then...
对不起
I'm sorry.
开开玩笑嘛!
We were just joking.
我知道,  开玩笑嘛!
I know you were just joking.
对不起,  真的,  我没什么
I'm sorry, I didn't mind at all.
你不要这样子嘛!
Don't be like this.
那你为什么要这样?
Then why are you like this?
你不要再碰我
Take your hand off me...
老板娘…
Boss!
你搞什么鬼?  我刚出去打一会麻将
What the hell are you doing? I was just out playing mah-jongg.
你看你把自己搞得,  人不像人、鬼不像鬼
Look at what you did to yourself? You look like a ghost.
你要不要脸、害不害躁?
Have you no shame? You are such a disgrace.
够了
Hey, enough!
阿梅喜欢怎样有她自己的权利
Mui has the right to dress how she wants.
你…你可以尊重别人吗?
Can't you respect that?
- 我觉得她今天很漂亮     - 是啊!
- I think she looks very nice today.     - Yes.
你说她不漂亮?
She looks great.
你不要太过份
Don't be mean to her.
我骂她关你们什么事?
I'll yell at her if I want to.
你们是什么狗东西?
Who the hell are you guys?
他们是我的朋友
They are my friends.
他们说的也是我想说的
I agree with them completely.
我觉得我现在很漂亮
I think I look beautiful now.
我也很喜欢我现在这个样子
And I like the way I am.
你要是不喜欢看,  你可以走开
If you don't like it you can simply go away.
你知不知道自己在跟谁说话?
Who do you think you're talking to?
我在跟你说话
I'm talking to you.
你是个没有人情味的老板娘
You are a mean and coldhearted boss.
他妈的…
You're asking for it!
你…你敢打我?  你…
How dare you hit me?
你造反啦!
I can't believe this.
你以为自己是谁?
Who do you think you are?
我就是我
lam who lam.
我是阿梅
I am Mui.
我…我告诉你妈去
I'm gonna tell your mother about this.
阿梅,  好
Mui, well done!
阿梅,  我们只是开玩笑,  你别见怪
We were just joking earlier. Please forgive us.
你刚才那个姿势好漂亮呀!
We weren't laughing at you, your sexy pose really was sexy.
真的吗?
Really?
我觉得…
I think...
我今天特别不像以前的阿梅
I think I've a little bit difference.
是呀!
Truly.
现在的阿梅已是一个很有自信的女孩
You've confidence right now.
我想跟你说件事
I want to tell you something.
什么事?
What's up?
我喜欢你
I like you!
我也喜欢你呀!
I like you, too!
那我们之间是爱情吗?
Is this love?
你…
You...
你是开玩笑吧?
You're kidding.
我是认真问你,  真的
No. I'm serious.
那当然不是爱情
Absolutely not. This is not love.
我们永远都是好朋友嘛!
We're friends forever...
那不是更好吗?
Don't you think it's good for us?
没什么
Okay! It's fine.
那…你以后也可以常常来找我
So you'll come to see me often?
鞋子破了,  我还可以帮你补
If your shoes are broken, I'll help you to repair them again.
不用了,  鞋子破了我就把它扔掉
No, thanks. If my shoes are broken, I must throw them away.
我们都要向前看嘛!
We should look forward to our future.
我永远都不要再穿破鞋子了
I'll never wear any broken shoes.
你不要这样子
Don't be like this.
干嘛?  你哭了?
What's wrong? You're crying?
你不要这样子
Don't do this.
我明白了
I understand.
谢谢你
Thank you!
来…  大家一块喝酒吧!
Come here!
嫂子,  你今天好漂亮
Mui, you are very nice today.
来,  干杯
Cheers!
赢了这一场,  我们就打入决赛
After winning this, we'll go to the finals.
决赛
Go to the finals!
千万不要轻敌
But we can't look down our opponent!
轻敌
Look down our opponent!
我们玉面双飞龙可不是浪得虚名的
We're the real powerful team.
想入决赛,  先问我们
I won't let you get into the finals.
有没有这么快呀?
Oh, my God! How come?
吊钢丝是吧?
It's the special effects?
雄哥,  早
Good morning, Hung!
早…
Good morning!
来,  过来坐…
Come here!
你这臭小子,  运气还真不错
You're a lucky guy.
居然让你找到这队绝活
You're so lucky to get this great team.
过奖…
Thank you.
其实你那些什么铁头功、心口碎大石
Actually, Iron Head and Iron Shirt are sorts of performance on the street.
全都是三脚猫的功夫
It's amusing for your guys to use kung fu to play soccer...
居然可以打入球场
...and then to get into the finals.
有两下子,  不错
You did a good job.
闲话少说
Don't waste our time!
决赛那天别踢了,  全队过来
Give up the finals and join into my Evil Team!
这次可不是空头支票
It's not a dishonour check.
你可以兑了现金再签合约
You can get the money before sign up with me.
这么大笔数目
It's lots of money.
真是打断腿都花不完
Probably, I can break my left leg and then get retired.
当然,  我和你是兄弟嘛!
Sure! We're brothers.
谢了,  雄哥
Thank you.
但是,  我怕受不起
But I think I can't take it.
什么意思?  你以为我会怕你?
What? Don't you think I'm afraid of you?
我看你那队有点意思,  想一起搞大
I think your team has great potential. So maybe we can join together.
做人要心胸广阔,  向前看
Don't be so easily upset. Think about your future.
不要老记仇,  好吗?
Forget the hostility. Okay?
雄哥,  我真的没记仇
Hung, I didn't keep the hostility in mind.
年轻时不懂事,  一切都是因果报应
I know, they were all my faults. I couldn't blame anyone.
你少给我装蒜
You're lying!
我早把你看透了,  你会不贪?
I know you much. You're so greedy!
真的让你看透了
You're right!
不单是我,  我整队人都贪
I'm so greedy. My team is greedy, too.
但是不是这张支票
But we've not an insatiable greed for money.
是全国冠军
We've an insatiable greed for the champion.
球场见
See you on the soccer field.
等等…  谢谢…
Wait! Wait for a monent! Thank you!
阿梅
Mui!
死掉啦!
She died already!
她怎么死的?
How come?
被我打死的
I killed her!
我不信
Oh, no!
阿梅武功那么好,  凭你打死她?
Mui is the master-hand of Tai Chi.
她一定死得很冤枉的
She must be treated unjustly!
那你想怎么样?
What do you want?
我要帮她报仇
Revenge!
傻啦!  我跟你开玩笑的
Don't be silly! It's just a joke!
她没死,  不过她不在这儿做了
She's still alive. She just doesn't work here.
为什么?
Why?
我们这儿明明叫甜在心馒头嘛!
You know, my stalling store is well-known of sweet steamed bread.
不知道那个傻丫头为什么突然间?
But now the steamed bread...
做的馒头又苦又咸
...she made becomes salty and bitter.
客人都不来了
She really ruins my business.
我也是被迫才炒她的呀!
I don't have another choice.
又苦又咸?
Salty and bitter?
是呀!
Yes.
这位大侠贵姓?  找她有什么事?
What's your name? Can I help?
没事了
No, thanks.
时间差不多啦!
It's time to go!
老板,  今天打算赢多少球?
Boss, how many goals do you expect to get today?
赢不一定非要进球
Getting goal is not the only way to win.
我还有更刺激的方法
I've a great idea to get win.
不可能
Impossible.
想不到美国这种新药这么厉害
I can't imagine how wonderful of the American medication!
还有球证、旁证
Actully the referee, linesman,
加上主办、协办所有的单位
soccer association, soccer federation and soccer committee...
全都是我的人
...all stand on my side.
怎么和我斗?
How can they fight with me?
没问题
No problem!
- 好棒     - 太棒啦!
- Great!     - Fit!
太神啦!
Wonderful!
界外球?
Throw-in?
当头踢过去根本是蓄意伤人
He did it on purpose.
你判界外球,  怎么做球证的?
How could you judge to be throw-in?
强雄,  你是踢球还是打人?
Hung, you're fighting or playing soccer?
我是打人,  怎么样?
Yes, we are. So what?
我要把你全队的人打得像你一样残废
I should break all you guys' legs and let you become cripples.
残废…
Cripples...
跟我斗?
How are you fight with me?
不好意思!  各位,  我要歇一会了
I'm sorry. I should take a break.
不要紧的,  你只是人离开
It's okay. You just physically leave us,
精神永远都会在这里
but your spirit will keep in our mind forever.
全都让开!  我来
Bend over! It's my turn.
六师弟
Sixth Small Brother!
有没有搞错?  这样子都不吹
What's wrong? Why don't you stop it?
上半场已经踢得半死了
All you guys are badly injured after the first half match.
下半场还怎么踢呀?
How can you play the second one?
回家吧!  下半场没得踢啦!
Go home! It's no way for you guys to play the second half!
没什么好看的啦!
Nothing interested!
要不要一会我下去跳舞撑撑场面?
Maybe I can go down to dance for a show.
跳舞也轮不到你跳,  我跳
No! It's not your turn. It's mine!
你们这群王八
Bullshit!
让开
Get out!
你们一定不想踢了
You guys don't want to play anymore!
谁呀…
Who did it?
有没有人见到?
Anyone saw it?
有种当我面打我
Hit my face, if you're brave enough!
别太使劲了
Rub gently.
我够赖皮了,  他们比我还下流
I can't imagine they're much lawless than me.
想不到我铁头功一世英名
I can't believe that...
临老被人开了花
...my reputation was ruined.
岂有此理!  我早就知道强雄会出阴招
I've already known that they must do something for us,
想不到他玩得这么过份
but I can't imagine they are so cruel.
魔鬼队没这么厉害
Evil Team is not so terrific.
肯定是打了针或者吃了药
They must take pills or have injection.
报警把他们抓起来
Call police!
我不管他们吃了什么
Anyway,
我们都要尽力踢下去
we should try our best to keep going.
最后我们一定会赢的
We'll get the final win!
我家突然着火了,  我先走了
My house is on fire, I need to run!
对不起,  我妈突然早产
I'm sorry. My mom is per mature birth right now.
我一定要回去帮忙
I should go home to take care of her.
拜托叫你妈晚点早产
Can you ask her to wait until the end of the game?
球踢了一半怎么可以走呢?
You can't give it up!
这哪是踢球?  要命的
They're not playing soccer. They're killing us!
拜托,  我求求你不要走呀!
I beg you. Please don't leave us!
我求你,  你不要求我了
I beg you back.
让我走吧!
Please let me go!
冷静点…
Calm down!
冷静点
没错,  他说得对
Yes, he's right!
无论任何情况我们都要踢完这场比赛
We should keep going.
现在我们只剩下八个人
Now, we just have eight players.
如果再有任何人受伤离场
If there is one more injured,
这场球我们就会输了
we'll fail.
他们的杀人射球,  我们一定要顶住
We must try our best to fight for the killer kick.
怎么顶?  你顶一球,  我顶三球?
How come? If you fight for one killer kick, I'll fight for three.
你说什么?
What are you talking about?
冷静点…
Calm down!
冷静点
别吵啦!
Shut up!
不知道我能不能顶住?
I'm not sure if I can fight for it.
少林罗汉阵
Shaolin Lou Han Array!
摆阵呀?
Array?
不堪一击
Can't stand for a shot!
- 顶得住吗?     - 顶得住
- Are you okay?     - I'm fine!
阿珍
Chun!
- 田鸡?     - 是呀!
- Tin?     - Yes.
这二十年来
I've kept a secret in my mind for many years,
有句话一直埋在我心里
but I really want to tell you at this moment.
其实…我爱你
Chun, I love you!
我们这样是不是有点残忍?
Do you think if we're so cruel?
- 不是     - 不是?
- I don't think so!     - Really?
那就再残忍一点
So we can be harsher.
兄弟,  上
Brothers! Go!
不会吧?
What?
小心点!  两个上
Be careful!
盯住呀!
Watch out!
有没有搞错?
Shit!
继续!  你死了没有?  别装蒜啦!
Hurry up! Don't act to be injured!
这都骗不倒你呀?  没事
You're so smart! I'm fine.
时间不多了,  出绝招
Time is almost out! Use the final attack!
绝招?
Final attack?
早就叫你回家了
It's useless for you guys...
还在这儿给我拖延时间
...to stall for time.
赢了
Win!
少林队
Shaolin Team.
你们现在只剩下七个人
Now, you just leave seven players.
如果你们没有后备球员上场
If you don't have any substitute players,
我就要正式终止这场比赛
I'll stop the game...
判你们少林队输了
...and announce that the game's over.
还有没有后补?
Any substitute players?
- 恭喜…     - 谢谢…
- Congratulations.      - Thank you.
还有我
My turn!
我是少林队的后补
I'm the substitute player.
我来当守门员
I'm the goalkeeper.
你怎么弄得跟外星人一样?
Why did you make up as E.T.?
我不会剪头发,  剃光了比较快点
I don't know how to cut my hair, so it will be good for me to shave it.
你来干什么?
For what?
我想帮你们比赛
I want to help you.
你怎么帮呀?
How can you do that?
你快点回火星吧!
Go back to the Mars,
地球是很危险的
the Earth is so dangerous.
我真的很想帮你呀!
I really want to help you.
你相信我,  让我试一下吧!
Trust me! Let me try!
- 不行     - 真的,  你看看…
- No way!     - You see,
你的鞋都破了
your shoes were broken.
穿这个吧!
Put these on.
在那边
The opposite side.
上去
Go!
好
Great!
小心啊!
Watch out!
怎么会这样?
What happened?
老板,  你小心呀!
Boss, watch out?
我小你老母
Damn it!
老板
Boss!
老板…
停车!  等等…
Wait! Stop it!